- [Trainer] Before we start adding operations
to our database and the corresponding endpoints,
we need to create our schema.
The schema is what it takes, the types of data
and the structure of your data your database takes.
In other words, if you define a first name key
to take only a string data,
the database will not accept anything else.
Therefore, the schema defines the rules related
to what your database can accept.
So let's go ahead and build this.
So what we're going to do is close the index.
You can also close the terminal if you want.
We can always restart the server after.
And we're going to go in the models folder
and then the player models file.
So let's go ahead and first of all,
we need to import mongoose
'cause we're going to need mongoose to create the schema.
Then we're going to create a variable with schema,
which will be the mongoose schema, like so.
And let me just remove this.
That was just my talent sense working.
And then we're going to create the official schema.
So we're going to make it available by exporting it.
And we're going to call it PlayerSchema = new Schema.
And this schema will take a few things.
So what we're going to do,
we're going to define defaults required
for a bunch of these keys.
And I'm going to explain it as I go.
So the first name will be of type string,
and then we're going to make it required.
'Cause we need at least a first name.
So that means if you don't have data when you submit
your player to the database, if we don't have a first name,
it's going to throw you an error.
We're going to do the same for the last name.
Actually, if you want to save time typing,
you can actually just copy
and paste exactly the same thing here
and just change it to last name.
And might as well do the same for email.
It's also going to be a string
and it also going to be required.
So let's go ahead and set an email.
Then we're going to do a phone,
and we won't make it required.
And this one will be of type number.
Then we're going to iscoach.
So basically, saying, is this particular player a coach?
And this is going to be a type boolean,
and you can set a default for some data will be false.
So basically, most people are not going to be a coach.
Then we're going to set a team,
and this is going to be of type string.
And then we're going to set a bunch of skills
for each of the players.
And the way we're going to set these up
are going to be a bit different than
what we've done so far in this schema.
So first of all, we're going to set it as a type number
and then we're going to use enums
to set specific values that this takes.
So the skill sets are going to be either evaluated
by a one, a two, or a three.
So one being the lowest number
and three being the highest number.
So the more numbers that these particular players have,
the highest the score they're going to have
across all their skill sets.
So we're going to do this for a couple
of specific skill sets for each player.
So speeds is going to be the first one.
Then we're going to have strength, same thing,
then endurance.
Then we're going to have ability
and then technique.
And this one, I'm going to set as plural, techniques.
Is this player tactical?
And finally, we're going to create
a date when this record was created.
So created on the score date,
type: Date, and then we're going to set
a default with Date.now.
Okay, so basically, you set up your schema.
So this schema's going to be exported
and then used as we enter new data.
And if we save this and we go into our terminal again,
and we want to make sure again that we're in the backend,
if you're using the same terminal every single time,
you shouldn't have to do this.
But I'm doing this because I'm closing it
and opening it, so I'm in the right folder.
NPM start, no issues whatsoever.
Okay, so now, the schema has been basically not passed down
to the actual mongoose instance yet,
but what you can do is check inside of Studio 3T
if, right now, you have any soccer player.
So what you need to do first is connect to the database,
which as you can see, I'm already connected
to it with Studio T.
So you can actually do this if you're not connected,
but I'm actually connected.
And then you go down the list of all the databases
that you have, collection, then click on players.
It should open this command here.
Run the command and then if you
don't have any players enter,
it should be empty here.
So if I run this, I don't have any players here.
So as we add new players,
we're going to see them in this database.
All right, so now, that we have our schema setup,
let's move on.